A Guide to the Papers of Carl Caskey Speidel 1923-1964
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
The Papers of Carl Caskey Speidel 1923-1964
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
MS-15
The collection consists of 2 Hollinger boxes of processed materials, 1 folio box containing large figure plates, 1 Hollinger box containing small films, and 4 record boxes containing large 16-mm reels of film and their canisters.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
not known
Biographical/Historical Information
Carl Caskey Speidel was born in Washington, D.C. on October 26, 1893. He received his Ph.B from Lafayette College 1914, and received his Ph.D. from Princeton University in 1918. He married Margaret Knowles on June 17, 1920, and began as an assistant professor of anatomy at the University of Virginia Medical School later that year.
In 1927, he won the Virginia Academy of Science's J. Shelton Horsley Research award, and in 1932 he received attention from the press when he took the $1000 prize from the American Association for the Advancement of Science for his research on nerve growth in living tadpoles. He continued to receive press attention throughout his career for his research films, which showed "living cells in action".
He was a trustee of the Marine Biology Laboratory in Woods Hole, Massachusetts, and a member of many professional science organizations. He retired from teaching at the Medical School in 1964, and died on September 19, 1982.
Scope and Content
The Carl Caskey Speidel Collection includes journal reprints and hand-drawn plates and figures used in journal articles. It also includes Speidel's press clippings, and materials from the classes he taught at the UVA Medical School. Also included in the collection are 74 reels of 16-mm film ranging in length from 100-450 feet of film documenting his research, with still photographs from the films, title lists and summaries of his films. The total length of the films is over 23,000 feet.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically by type of document, starting with journal reprints, followed by figure plates, class materials, press clippings, and films.
Contents List
- Journal reprint from the Proceedings of the Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine, with H.E. Jordan: "Leucocytes in Relation to the Mechanism of thyroid-accelerated metamorphosis in the larval frog" 1923 (Box-folder 01:01)
- Journal reprint from the Anatomical Record, with H.E. Jordan: "The Fate of the Mammalian Lymphocyte" 1923 October (Box-folder 01:02)
- Journal Reprint from the Journal of Experimental Medicine, with H.E. Jordan: "Blood Cell formation and distribution in relation to the mechanism of thyroid-accelerated metamorphosis in the larval frog" 1923 November 1 (Box-folder 01:03)
- Journal reprint from the Proceedings of the Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine, with H.E. Jordan: "The Fundamental Erythrocytopoietic stimulus" 1924 (Box-folder 01:04)
- Journal reprint from the Journal of Experimental Medicine, with H.E. Jordan: "The Behavior of the Leucocytes during coincident regeneration and thyroid-induced metamorphosis in the frog larva with a consideration of growth factors" 1924 July 1 (Box-folder 01:05)
- Journal reprint from the Journal of the American Medical Association: "The effect of Thyroid Administration on the eye of the frog tadpole: A possible additional factor in the production of goitrous exophthalmos" 1924 July 12 (Box-folder 01:06)
- Journal reprint from the Biological Bulletin: "Endocrine glands and bilateral symmetry: observations upon forelimb eruption in frog larvae under treatment with thyroid and thymus extracts" 1925 May (Box-folder 01:07)
- Journal reprint from the Anatomical Record: "Studies of Hyperthyroidism I. Experimental hyperthyroidism and the germ glands in amphibians with special reference to the primitive interstitial tissue" 1925 September 25 (Box-folder 01:08)
- Journal reprint from the American Journal of Anatomy: "Studies of Hyperthyroidism II. The significance of changes in the thymus gland of thyroid-treated frog tadpoles" 1926 March 15 (Box-folder 01:09)
- Journal reprint from the Journal of Experimental Medicine: "Studies of Hyperthyroidism III. Bile pigment production and erythrocyte destruction in thyroid-treated amphibian larvae" 1926 May 1 (Box-folder 01:10)
- Journal reprint from the Proceedings of the Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine, with H.E. Jordan: "Erythrocytophagic capacity of the hepatic peritoneum in the splenectomized horned toad, Phrynosoma solare" 1928 (Box-folder 01:11)
- Journal reprint from the Proceedings of the Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine, with H.E. Jordan: "Origin and proliferation of thrombocytes in splenectomized salamanders" 1929 (Box-folder 01:12)
- Journal reprint from the American Journal of Anatomy, with H.E. Jordan: "Blood-cell formation in the horned toad, Phrynosoma solare" 1929 January 15 (Box-folder 01:13)
- Journal reprint from the Anatomical Record: "Studies of Hyperthyroidism V. Observations upon the posterior lymph heart and lymph vessels in living frog larvae under treatment with thyroid extract" 1929 February 25 (Box-folder 01:14)
- Journal reprint from the American Journal of Anatomy, with H.E. Jordan: "The hemocytopoietic effect of splenectomy in the salamander, Triturus viridescens" 1930 July 15 (Box-folder 01:15)
- Journal reprint from the American Journal of Anatomy, with H.E. Jordan: "Blood formation in cyclostomes" 1930 November 15 (Box-folder 01:16)
- Journal reprint from the Journal of Morphology and Physiology, with H.E. Jordan: "Blood formation in the African lungfish, under normal conditions of prolonged estivation and recovery" 1931 June 5 (Box-folder 01:17)
- Journal reprint from the Journal of Experimental Zoology: "Studies of living nerves I. The movements of individual sheath cells and nerve sprouts correlated with the process of myelin-sheath formation in amphibian larvae" 1932 February 5 (Box-folder 01:18)
- Journal reprint from the American Journal of Anatomy: "Studies of living nerves II. Activities of ameboid growth cones, sheath cells, and myelin segments, as revealed by prolonged observation of individual nerve fibers in frog tadpoles" 1933 January 15 (Box-folder 01:19)
- Journal reprint from The Scientific Monthly: "The Growth and repair of nerves" 1933 July (Box-folder 01:20)
- German reprint: "Growth, Irritation, and Repair of Nerves." Postcard (German), requesting reprint 1934 (Box-folder 01:21)
- ...Journal reprint from the Journal of Comparative Neurology: "Studies of Living Nerves III. Phenomena of nerve irritation and recovery, degeneration and repair" 1935 February 15 (Box-folder 01:22)
- Journal reprint from the Biological Bulletin: "Studies of Living Nerves IV. Growth, regeneration, and myelination of peripheral nerves in salamanders" 1935 February (Box-folder 01:23)
- Journal reprint from the Cold Spring Harbor Symposia on Quantitative Biology: "The Experimental Induction of visible structural changes in single nerve fibers in living frog tadpoles" 1936 (Box-folder 01:24)
- Journal reprint from the Journal of Comparative Neurology: "Studies of living nerves V. Alcoholic neuritis and recovery" 1936 June 15 (Box-folder 01:25)
- Journal reprint from the Scientific Monthly: "Changes in nerve fibers during alcoholic intoxication and recovery" 1937 February (Box-folder 01:26)
- Journal reprint from the American Journal of Anatomy: "Studies of living muscles I. Growth, injury and repair of striated muscle, as revealed by prolonged observations of individual fibers in living frog tadpoles" 1938 January 15 (Box-folder 01:27)
- Journal reprint from the American Journal of Anatomy: "Studies of living muscles II. Histological changes in single fibers of striated muscle during contraction and clotting" 1939 November 15 (Box-folder 01:28)
- Journal reprint from the Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society: "Studies of living nerves VI. Effects of metrazol on tissues of frog tadpoles with special reference to the injury and recovery of individual nerve fibers" 1940 (Box-folder 01:29)
- Journal reprint from the Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society: "Studies of living nerves VIII. Histories of nerve endings in frog tadpoles subjected to various injurious treatments" 1942 January (Box-folder 01:30)
- Journal reprint from the Journal of Comparative Neurology: "Studies of living nerves VII. Growth adjustments of cutaneous terminal arborizations" 1942 February 16 (Box-folder 01:31)
- Journal reprint from the Journal of Comparative Neurology: "Correlated studies of sense organs and nerves of the lateral-line in living frog tadpoles I. Regeneration of de-nervated organs" 1947 August (Box-folder 01:32)
- Journal reprint from the American Journal of Anatomy: "Correlated studies of sense organs and nerves of the lateral-line in living frog tadpoles II. The trophic influence of specific nerve supply as revealed by prolonged observations of de-nervated and reinnervated organs" 1948 March (Box-folder 01:33)
- Journal reprint from the Scientific Monthly: "Nerves in Vivo" 1948 September (Box-folder 01:34)
- Journal reprint from the American Journal of Anatomy: "Correlated Studies of sense organs and nerves of the lateral-line in living frog tadpoles IV. Patterns of Vagus nerve regeneration after single and multiple operations" 1964 January (Box-folder 01:36)
- Journal reprint from the International Review of Cytology: "In Vivo studies of myelinated nerve fibers" 1964 (Box-folder 01:37)
- Proceedings of the American Association of Anatomists Seventy-ninth meeting with list of officers and members 1966 July (Box-folder 01:38)
- The Biological Bulletin, Vol. 141, no. 1, including Action of 1970 Annual Meeting 1971 August (Box-folder 01:39)
- Draft of "Correlated Studies" IV [1963] (Box-folder 01:40)
- "Correlated Studies" IV and V extra data [1963] (Box-folder 01:41)
- "Correlated Studies" V draft, original and extra data, and figure descriptions ND (Box-folder 01:42)
- 1 of 3 figures from "Growth and Repair of Nerves" [1933 July] (Box-folder 02:01)
- 7 of 9 figures from "Correlated Studies I" [1947 August] (Box-folder 02:02)
- 7 of 7 figures from "Nerves in Vivo," 1 plate [1948 September] (Box-folder 02:03)
- 14 of 15 figures from "Correlated Studies II" [1948 March] (Box-folder 02:04)
- 10 of 10 figures from "Correlated Studies III" 1949 July (Box-folder 02:05)
- 19 figures from "Correlated Studies IV" 1964 January (Box-folder 02:06)
- 28 figures from "In Vivo Studies" [1964] (Box-folder 02:07)
- Miscellaneous plates and drawings ND (Box-folder 02:08)
- Correspondence between Speidel and John A. Moore 1956 April (Box-folder 02:09)
  The letters are in regard to a paper titled, "The Invasion of Tadpole Tissues by the Ciliated Protozoon Tetrahymena" by Carl Caskey Speidel. Moore was the editor of the "Journal of Morphology."
- "The Invasion of Tadpole Tissues by the Ciliated Protozoon Tetrahymena" by Carl Caskey Speidel [1956] (Box-folder 02:10)
  The typed manuscript includes an explanation of figures, bibliography, and footnotes.
- figures for "The Invasion of Tadpole Tissues by the Ciliated Protozoon Tetrahymena" by Carl Caskey Speidel [1956] (Box-folder 02:11)
  The 32 photographs are on 15 boards.
- Groups for dissection [1952-1953] (Box-folder 02:12)
- Anatomy 1 (Gross Anatomy) Class materials 1929-1949 (Box-folder 03:01)
- Osteology class materials 1950-1954 (Box-folder 03:02)
- Neuroanatomy class materials 1940-1964 (Box-folder 03:03)
- "Atlas of Cross Section Anatomy of the Brain" revised by A.T. Rasmussen 1951 (Box-folder 03:04)
- Virginia Academy of Science J. Shelton Horsley Research Award 1927 May (Box-folder 03:05)
- University of Virginia Alumni News: "Virginia Anatomist Wins Award" (p. 85) 1932 January (Box-folder 03:06)
- New York Times: "Finds nerve secrets sought for 70 years; wins science prize" 1932 January 2 (Box-folder 03:07)
- Science News Letter: "Nerves grow as if with aim AAAS prize paper shows" 1932 January 9 (Box-folder 03:08)
- Time Magazine: "Nerves and $1000" (p. 32) 1932 January 11 (Box-folder 03:09)
- New York Times, photograph with caption regarding AAAS prize 1932 January 17 (Box-folder 03:10)
- College Topics: "What Speidel Proved" 1932 January 18 (Box-folder 03:11)
- Science News Letter, mention in 'Recognitions and Awards' section 1932 December 24 (Box-folder 03:12)
- Science News Letter: "Motion Pictures made of growing nerve fibers" 1933 January 21 (Box-folder 03:13)
- The Literary Digest: "Watching nerves grow and repair themselves" 1933 August 26 (Box-folder 03:14)
- The Washington Post: "Tipsy Tadpoles tell Scientist a Spree a Day isn't too much" 1934 March 29 (Box-folder 03:15)
- Boston Herald: "What Intoxication does to your Nerves" 1934 September 2 (Box-folder 03:16)
- The State (S.C.): "Science Studies Living Tissues," cartoon and caption 1934 September 9 (Box-folder 03:17)
- Science News Letter: "How Sprees Ruin Nerves" (p. 170) 1934 September 15 (Box-folder 03:18)
- New York Times: "Dr. Speidel asserts alcohol causes nerves of tadpoles to leave the skin" (p. 11) 1935 November 20 (Box-folder 03:19)
- American Weekly: "New hope for little victims of infantile paralysis" 1939 July 2 (Box-folder 03:20)
- The Collecting Net: "Living cells in action demonstrated in motion pictures" 1939 September 2 (Box-folder 03:21)
- American Weekly: "Science explains the 'shiner'" 1944 January 30 (Box-folder 03:22)
- The Courier-Journal (KY): "U. of L. to see films showing cells growing" 1946 January 8 (Box-folder 03:23)
- "Speeded cell movies eyed as disease aid" [1946] (Box-folder 03:24)
- The Oregonian: "Science motion pictures study life in tadpoles" 1946 March 7 (Box-folder 03:25)
- Nantucket Town Crier: "Tadpole is indispensable in gathering of laboratory data, professor relates here" 1953 August 14 (Box-folder 03:26)
- Grafton Sentinel (WV); photograph, cartoon and caption ND (Box-folder 03:27)
- Muscle photos, Woods Hole, 23 photographs [1936] (Box-folder 03:28)
- Dr. Speidel Sigma Xi Tour, 9 negatives 1945 November 9 (Box-folder 03:29)
- Speidel Drawings: nerves and muscles, 5 negatives, 1 photograph 1945 December 28 (Box-folder 03:30)
- Vishniac photos of macrophages, 16 photographs [1946] (Box-folder 03:31)
- Lymph vessels, nerves, 25 photographs with envelope [1947] (Box-folder 03:32)
- Vishniac life films, nerve, endothelium lymph, macrophages, 43 photos and envelope [1947] (Box-folder 03:33)
- Marine Biological Laboratory, 7 photos, 4 slides, letter 1964 October 10 (Box-folder 03:34)
- Nerve growth cones, photos from films, 17 photographs ND (Box-folder 03:35)
- Letter to Speidel regarding research film archive at Marine Biological Laboratory 1938 September 26 (Box-folder 03:36)
- Motion pictures titles lists 1937-1945 (Box-folder 03:37)
- Short reviews of films (labeled 1-23) [1950] (Box-folder 03:38)
- Obituaries from The Daily Progress, the Washington Post; Entry from "Who was Who in America" 1982 September 22 (Box-folder 03:39)
- Label: "540," no titles, 100 feet of film 1966 July (Box-folder 04:01)
- Label: "541," no titles, 100 feet of film 1966 July (Box-folder 04:02)
- Label: "542," no titles, 100 feet of film 1966 September (Box-folder 04:03)
- Label: "543," no titles, 100 feet of film 1966 September (Box-folder 04:04)
- Label: "544," no titles, 100 feet of film 1966 September (Box-folder 04:05)
- Label: "545," no titles, 100 feet of film 1966 September (Box-folder 04:06)
- Label: "546," no titles, 100 feet of film 1966 September (Box-folder 04:07)
- Label: "Arabacia Development, Original", Titles: "The Early Development of the Sea Urchin Egg (Arabacia)," 100 feet of film 1951 November (Box-folder 04:08)
- Label: "Sea Urchin Development, Hampden-Sidney," Titles: "Living Cells in Action," 100 feet of film 1955 January (Box-folder 04:09)
- Label: "Arabacia Temporary 9," Titles: "16 minute UV to prisms and gastrulae, recovery after 20 minutes," 100 feet of film 1963 September (Box-folder 04:10)
- Label: "Sea Urchin Arabacia Early Development," Titles: "Living Cells in Action," 100 feet of film ND (Box-folder 04:11)
- No Label, Titles: "Early Development of the sea urchin egg," 100 feet of film ND (Box-folder 04:12)
- Label: 2 "Myelin Adjustments Original Film," First Title: "Myelin Sheath Adjustments," 400 feet of film ND (Box-folder 05:01)
- Label: 4 "Muscle," First Title: "Some Histological Changes in Muscle Fibers," 420 feet of film ND (Box-folder 05:02)
- Label: 5 "Reaction to skeletal and cardiac muscle fiber injury," First Title: "Reactions of Skeletal and Cardiac muscle fibers to injury," 300 feet of film ND (Box-folder 05:03)
- Label: 6 "GI circ. connect luecos," First title: "Movements of various types of leucocytes (lymphocytes, monocytes, macrophages, granulocytes)," 325 feet of film ND (Box-folder 05:04)
- Label: 7a "Muscle," First Title: "Varieties of Muscle Contraction. Uncoordinated twitches, alcohol stimulation," 400 feet of film ND (Box-folder 05:05)
- Label: 7b "Muscle, G2," First Title: "Living Cells in Action," 430 feet of film ND (Box-folder 05:06)
- Label: 7c "Muscle 7(2), 2nd Duplicate of #7 Muscle," First Title: "Living Cells in Action," 400 feet of film ND (Box-folder 05:07)
- Label: 8&9 "C.C. Speidel, 9&8," First Title: "Method of mounting a frog tadpole for microscopic observations," 400 feet of film ND (Box-folder 05:08)
- Label: 10 "Activities of living Nerves, UVA," First Title: "Activities of Living Nerves," 420 feet of film ND (Box-folder 05:09)
- Label: 11 "Nerves Dupl.," First Title: "Another Dividing Sheath cell with conspicuous chromosomes," 400 feet of film N (Box-folder 05:10)
- Label: 13 "Dupl. 13," First Title: "Growth cones of nerve fibers in salamanders," 350 feet of film ND (Box-folder 05:11)
- Label: 14 "Activities in Living Nerves, Metrazol and Alcohol," First Title: Activities in Living Nerves," 400 feet of film ND (Box-folder 05:12)
- Label: 15 "Aberrant fiber oriented perpendicularly to adjacent fibers," First Title: "Aberrant nerve fibers oriented perpendicularly to adjacent fibers (April 29)," 420 feet of film ND (Box-folder 05:13)
- Label: 18 "18, Speidel," First Title: "Fiber with greatly swollen cross striae incapable of contraction," 200 feet of film ND (Box-folder 05:14)
- Label: 19 "Lymph Vessels, Macros, RBC," First Title: (Canister is stuck, so not known) ND (Box-folder 05:15)
- Label: 21 "Speidel 21," First Title: n/a, 350 feet of film ND (Box-folder 06:01)
- Label: 23 "C.C. Speidel," First Title: "Macrophages and muscle debris one day after injury," 300 feet of film ND (Box-folder 06:02)
- Label: 27 "Tantalum," First Title: "Local Reaction of Cells to Tantalum powder during the first day (5-27 hours)," 400 feet of film ND (Box-folder 06:03)
- Label: 30 "Implants: tantalum, silk, nylon, tar, paraffin, carmine, zinc oxide," First Title: "Reaction of cells in tadpoles to implanted substances," 410 feet of film ND (Box-folder 06:04)
- Label: 33.2 "Tetrahymena, 33.2," First Title: "Invasion of tadpole tissues by the ciliated protozoan, tetrahymena," 400 feet of film ND (Box-folder 06:05)
- Label: 34 "Retina Brain," First Title: "Cells of brain and retina in tissue culture," 420 feet of film ND (Box-folder 06:06)
- Label: 35 "Tissues attacked by ciliates," First Title: "Changes in structure of tissues under attack by ciliates (Balantdium, tetrahymena)," 400 feet of film ND (Box-folder 06:07)
- Label: 36.1 "Histological changes in tissues of tadpoles after x-ray irradiation as recorded by cinemicrography," First Title: "Histological changes in tissues of tadpoles after x-ray irradiation," 400 feet of film ND (Box-folder 06:08)
- Label: 37a "Regen X-ray," First Title: "Tissue changes in regenerating zones of irradiated tadpoles," 400 feet of film ND (Box-folder 06:09)
- Label: 37b "Speidel silent 37," First Title: "Tadpole tissues during centrifuging, as observed with the centrifuging microscope," 300 feet of film ND (Box-folder 06:10)
- Label: 38 "Lateral line organs showing vagus nerve and at end, orange granule clumps in color," First Title: n/a, 420 feet of film ND (Box-folder 06:11)
- Label: 38.2 "X-ray Tetra," First Title: Effects of x-ray irradiation on cells of tadpoles," 400 feet of film ND (Box-folder 06:12)
- Label: 39 "Nerves Gr. tips etc.," First Title: "Long hair-like processes protrude from lateral-line organ sensory cell," 400 feet of film ND (Box-folder 06:13)
- Label: 40 "Some cellular movements in newly hatched tadpoles," First Title: "Some cellular movements in newly hatched tadpoles," 350 feet of film ND (Box-folder 06:14)
- Label: 41 "Vagus regen & aberr vagus," First Title: "Aberrant tip of lateral line nerve growing in reverse direction makes little progress," 375 feet of film ND (Box-folder 06:15)
- Label: 42 "Lateral line nerves in sense organs in tadpoles," First Title: "Lateral line nerves and sense organs in tadpoles," 400 feet of film ND (Box-folder 07:01)
- Label: 45&50 "LLO and Mustard," First Title: "Orange granules disappear under the usual laboratory conditions," 350 feet of film ND (Box-folder 07:02)
- Label: 48 "Speidel 48," First Title: "Effects of mustard compounds on tissues of tadpoles," 400 feet of film ND (Box-folder 07:03)
- Label: 49 "Mustard 2, silk nylon tantalum wire," First Title: "Mustard treatment induces 'sickness' of leucocytes in venules though not in arteries," 400 feet of film ND (Box-folder 07:04)
- Label: 51 "Speidel 51," First Title: "March 27th terminal myelin segment and nearby sheath cells," 250 feet of film ND (Box-folder 07:05)
- Label: 54 "Nerve Growth," First Title: "Growth of nerve fibers," 425 feet of film ND (Box-folder 07:06)
- Label: 55 "Muscle Cell," First Title: "Adjustments of nerve endings," 420 feet of film ND (Box-folder 07:07)
- Label: 56 "Reaction of cells in frog tadpoles to implants of tantalum," First Title: "Reaction of cells in frog tadpoles to implants of tantalum," 400 feet of film ND (Box-folder 07:08)
- Label: 57 "Tantalum effects," First Title: "Tantalum laden macrophage in blood vessel (5 days)," 300 feet of film ND (Box-folder 07:09)
- Label: 58 "Holinger Study," First Title: "Tantalum wire implants after 5 hours with leucocytes clustering along it's surface," 300 feet of film ND (Box-folder 07:10)
- Label: 61 "Holinger study, silk," First Title: "History of silk implant for 57 days," 410 feet of film ND (Box-folder 07:11)
- Label: 62 "Holinger study, silk, nylon, tant wire," First Title: "Silk Implant after 7, 16, 39, 55, 64, 73 days," 300 feet of film ND (Box-folder 07:12)
- Label: 66 "Catgut, starch, talc, aluminum, magnesium threads in," First Title: "Reactions of cells in tadpoles," 400 feet of film ND (Box-folder 07:13)
- Label: 67 "Tetrahymena," First Title: "Invasion of tadpole tissue by ciliated protozoan, tetrahymena," 375 feet of film ND (Box-folder 07:14)
- Label: 68 "Brain Retina frog, rat," First Title: "Cells of brain and retina in tissue culture," 400 feet of film ND (Box-folder 07:15)
- Label: 70 "Tetra? Fission and encystment of ciliate," First Title: n/a, 300 feet of film ND (Box-folder 07:16)
- Label: A1 "Arabacia 1, x-ray, UV," First Title: "Radiation induced modifications in developing sea urchins," 430 feet of film ND (Box-folder 08:01)
- Label: A2 "Arabacia 2, Differential effects of x-ray and ultraviolet irradiation of Arabacia gametes," First Title: "Differential effects of x-ray and ultraviolet radiation on Arabacia gametes," 400 feet of film ND (Box-folder 08:02)
- Label: A3a "#3 Arabacia original," First Titles: Effects on density and cleavage of gamete irradiation in Arabacia," 300 feet of film ND (Box-folder 08:03)